Those who are from Starehe Boys,
if you're an alumni of Starehe Boys,
I I went to Starehe, by the way,
to preach the gospel.
So,
I was told they have only one rule.
Be at the right time,
uh uh be be in the right place,
doing the right thing
at the right time. That was the rule.
So, if you're found sleeping,
the teacher will come and ask you, "Are
you in the right place?" Yes.
"Are you doing the right thing?" Yes.
"Is it the right time?" No.
So, if you're found in class when people
are eating,
the question will be, "Are you in the
right place?" Yes.
"Doing the right thing?"
"Is it the right time?"
No.
And so, that was the summary of their
school rule.
And I feel like telling you,
spiritually,
be in the right place,
at the right time,
doing the right thing,
and everything will fall in place.
Because some things you're doing are not
wrong,
but the timing is the problem.
Some places you are are wrong, though
what you're doing is right. So, may the
Lord give you the wisdom to be where
you're supposed to be. Hallelujah.
Amen.
Let me appreciate the pastors that are
here. Pastor Eugene, God bless you.
Thank you for leading us.
Uh Pastor Ronnie, may God bless you.
Uh thank you for what you're doing. Oh,
the wife of Pastor Rashid, thank you for
leading us in the morning for prayer.
The Lord is launching the women. We were
working on the men, because we know once
the men are okay, the women will be
okay.
Thank you, Pastor Kanjagwa, with your
wife. May God bless you.
Let's clap for them. Pastor William, may
God bless you.
Pastor Anita,
may God bless you. Thank you for what
you are doing with the one soul
movement. Indeed, it's a movement. And I
see the Lord just doing wonders. These
are the days of revival, and the burden
is coming for souls. Pastor Kevin with
your wife, may God bless you.
Um the wife to Evangelist Kibali, God
bless you.
Uh Pastor
Tamani, God bless you. Minister Sylvia,
God bless you. See my friend Edwin and
also my friend Allan is around. God
bless all of you. Hallelujah.
I've also mentioned you in my spirit.
And also, help me appreciate the
presence of my wife, who is also here
with us.
Mum Claudia, God bless you.
I hear today there is a fire chat, so we
might sneak in.
Either to get the fire or to hear the
chat.
I want to briefly talk about
the believer's authority.
When you teach spirituality,
and you miss in the balance,
you It is very possible to generate what
we call
demon consciousness.
Whatever gives you victory in the walk
of faith
is the consciousness that dominates your
spirit.
What gives you victory
in your walk of faith
is the consciousness that dominates your
spirit.
And there are two types of
consciousness.
Number one, demonic consciousness.
And number two,
Christ consciousness.
These are the two consciousness
that can be activated when we are
preaching and when we are teaching.
So, you can carry a demonic
consciousness
where all you see in life is demons.
Everything in your life, you interpret
it from a demonic level.
You just see a dark cat
going round and you conclude that's a
demon.
But when you see a white cat, you have
no problem. Please, stop being a racist.
And there are people who are like that.
They see devils.
And sometimes it's very uncomfortable to
even hang out with them.
Because even basic things like food,
they want to know who was the farmer.
Is he born again?
Was this chicken dedicated to demons?
Listen, I know there is warfare.
But I can assure you
if THERE IS NO BALANCE IN OUR THEOLOGY,
we can produce demon-conscious
believers.
And a demon-conscious believer is a
defeated believer.
And secondly, you can produce a
Christ-conscious
believer.
So, there is Christ-consciousness.
SO, AGAIN,
THERE IS ALSO A BALANCE needed
because there are people who are
ignorant of the kingdom of darkness.
And some of THEM ARE EVEN TERRORIZED
spiritually because if there is no
balance in our theology, ideally, it
means
you might be Christ-conscious, which is
the goal,
but ignorant
of the devices
and how the enemy operates.
And that's why in 2 Corinthians
chapter number two
beginning from verse eight
I want you to see.
Therefore, I URGE YOU
TO REAFFIRM YOUR LOVE TO HIM.
CONTINUE. We're leaving
For to this end I also wrote that I
might put you to the test whether you
are obedient in all things.
Now, whom you forgive anything, I also
forgive.
For if indeed I have forgiven anything,
I have forgiven that one for your sake
in the presence of Christ.
And then he THROWS A VERY POWERFUL
SCRIPTURE. Let's all read. Lest Satan
SHOULD TAKE ADVANTAGE OF US. HOLD IT
THERE.
This is a matter of forgiveness.
I KNOW THE SECOND PART, WE ALWAYS
MENTION IT.
SO, PAUL IS SPEAKING ON THE
ACTUALIZATION
OF the work of a believer.
AND HE'S SAYING, YOU KNOW, IF YOU
FORGIVE I HAVE NO PROBLEM. THE ONE YOU
HAVE FORGIVEN, I WILL ALSO FORGIVE.
Because there are people who carry
corporate beef.
SOMEONE CAN HATE YOU ON BEHALF OF THEIR
FRIEND.
SO, IF YOU CAN DO THAT, ALSO FORGIVE ON
BEHALF OF YOUR FRIEND.
AND HE'S TELLING THEM, I ALSO DON'T HOLD
THEM INTO ACCOUNTABILITY. THEN HE COMES
AND TELLS US, LEST SATAN SHOULD TAKE
ADVANTAGE OF US.
FOR WE ARE NOT IGNORANT OF HIS DEVICES.
SO, WHEN WE ARE GOING TO SPIRITUAL
WARFARE, we apply this scripture.
BUT WE DON'T UNDERSTAND THE CONTEXT THAT
THE DEVICES OF THE ENEMY is when there
is a MALFUNCTIONALITY
of our walk and ordinance.
Let's read it in NLT.
So, WHEN WE DO NOT ABIDE BY THE
STANDARDS AND PRINCIPLES OF HEAVEN, THAT
THING BECOMES A DEVICE. SO,
UNFORGIVENESS CAN BECOME A DEVICE.
BITTERNESS CAN BECOME A DEVICE.
TOO MUCH TALKING CAN BECOME A DEVICE
THAT THE ENEMY WILL USE TO LAUNCH WAR.
SO, THAT SATAN WILL NOT OUTSMART US.
FOR WE ARE FAMILIAR WITH HIS evil
schemes.
He's a schemer. Let's look it at message
passion.
Look at it.
Message.
So, as we as we are getting there,
after all, we do not want to unwittingly
give Satan to an opening for yet more
mischief. We are not oblivious to his
sly ways. Are you seeing the word
openings?
Are you seeing the word openings?
So, when we begin to look at this
scripture, it is clear
that automatically a believer should not
be ignorant.
You should not live as if you are not
aware THAT THERE IS AN ENEMY, AND THAT
ENEMY operates with certain devices.
Colossians
chapter number two, FROM VERSE 13 ALL
THE WAY TO 15.
Colossians chapter number two, from
verse 13 all the way to 15.
The Bible says, everybody read. When
when you are stuck. Let's all read, 1 2
3.
When you are stuck in your old sin dead
life, YOU ARE INCAPABLE OF responding to
God.
God brought YOU ALIVE RIGHT ALONG with
Christ. Think of it all.
THINK OF IT. ALL SINS FORGIVEN. SO, that
scripture is is it's a mystery. When you
are stuck in your OLD WAY,
THE SLATE WIPED CLEAN.
THAT OLD ARREST WARRANT CANCELED AND
nailed to Christ's cross.
He stripped all THE SPIRITUAL TYRANTS IN
THE UNIVERSE OF THEIR SHAM AUTHORITY AT
THE CROSS AND MARCHED THEM NAKED through
the streets.
YOU YOU SEE, THE SCHEMES AND THE DEVICES
OF the enemy can only be activated if
THE WALK OF A BELIEVER IS NOT accurate
according to the teaching and the
standards of THE KINGDOM.
WHEN PAUL IS TALKING ABOUT THE DEVICES,
IT ACTUALLY MEANS THAT THERE ARE CERTAIN
OPENINGS A BELIEVER CAN SET AND GIVE THE
ENEMY A GROUND AND A FOOT of attack.
So, WHEN YOU ARE NOT IGNORANT OF THEM,
YOU TAKE OF THE DOORS.
Can I tell you something about even
forgiveness?
Pastor Peter, I come TO REALIZE
THE FIRST temptation of Jesus,
the devil did not hide.
He approached him in the wilderness.
And he tempted him.
And Jesus overcame him.
Turn this what turn this stone into
bread. He He
Cast thyself and angels will hold you.
He overcame.
Bow down and worship me, and I'm going
to give you the world and its glory. He
overcame. The Bible says the devil left.
Because Jesus told him, "Get behind me,
Satan."
The devil left, but the scripture there
says
waiting for another
opportune
opportunity.
So, he left, BUT THE AGENDA NEVER LEFT.
SO, THE FIRST TIME HE CAME AS THE DEVIL,
BUT THE SECOND TIME
THAT OPPORTUNE
and that opportune time
began TO MANIFEST BECAUSE THE CORE
REASON OF LUCIFER was that Jesus will
not go to the cross.
So, Jesus has selected his three men,
James, Peter, and John.
We see Peter
when he was asked about, "WHO AM I?"
PETER ANSWERS and says, "You are THE
CHRIST, THE SON OF THE LIVING GOD."
IN THAT SAME CHAPTER
UH MATTHEW CHAPTER NUMBER 18, I THINK.
IN THAT SAME CHAPTER WHERE PETER got it
right,
IT IS THE SAME CHAPTER WHERE HE TOLD
HIM, "You cannot go to the cross."
So, he knew who Jesus was, but he did
not understand the assignment of Jesus.
NOW, THE DEVIL COMES THROUGH PETER.
THE WORD HERE IS THROUGH PETER
AND TELLS JESUS, "YOU CANNOT GO TO THE
CROSS.
IN FACT, I'M GOING TO DEFEND YOU.
ANYONE THAT TOUCHES YOU, I'LL MAKE sure
that I deal with him."
Guess what? Jesus looked at Peter
and said, "Get behind me, SATAN." THE
VERY STATEMENT OF THE TEMPTATION.
FOLLOW
SO, THE FIRST TIME JESUS MET THE DEVIL
HIMSELF,
OUT OF ENCOUNTER, JESUS KNEW WHO LUCIFER
WAS.
THE SECOND TIME, THE MOUTH OF PETER WAS
HIJACKED BY LUCIFER.
I want you to understand.
"Get behind me, Satan. You are an
offense to me, for you are not mindful
of the things of God,
but of the things of man." It's still in
Matthew 16, where Peter answered
correctly.
Matthew 16:16, 16:18, is where he said,
"You are the son of God." 16:16, I
think. And And he said, "Flesh and blood
does not reveal this to you." In the
same scripture, I
THE ONE THAT NOW WE CAN ALL SAY, "THIS
MAN CAN GIVE US DIRECTION concerning
Jesus." That's the man the devil uses
his mouth.
And he tells the people, HE TELLS JESUS,
"YOU WILL NOT GO TO THE CROSS."
SIMON PETER ANSWERED AND SAID, "YOU ARE
THE CHRIST, THE SON OF THE LIVING GOD."
SEE?
Is it in the same chapter?
SO, PASTOR RONNIE, IF THAT was a
meeting,
and Jesus says, "Ronnie, flesh and blood
does not reveal this to you.
And from today, you are not Ronnie, you
are Peter, Pedro's stability."
That's theology without function.
So, the man knows who Jesus is, but he
doesn't know the assignment of Christ.
And the same man,
the devil partners with him.
And he tells Jesus, "You can't go to the
cross." Guess what the Bible says? He
told him, "Get behind me, Satan."
I discovered
the next level, the opportune time, the
devil does not come like the devil.
He might be with you.
AND THAT'S WHY YOUR EYES IN THE SPIRIT
MUST be opened.
To see THE DEVIL BEHIND PETER.
OTHERWISE, YOU WILL FIGHT PETER, BUT THE
PROBLEM IS NOT PETER. Until you locate
the source,
you are fighting the wrong battle.
SOME OF THE PEOPLE YOU CALL YOUR
ENEMIES, THEY ARE NOT your enemies.
Locate
Can I speak today?
If the DEVIL CAN ENTER IN THE INNER
CIRCLE of the three, who told you the
devil cannot use the mouth of your wife
or husband?
Edwin, there are days
I have to be safe here.
THERE ARE TIMES YOU NEED TO LOOK AT THAT
PERSON AND realize this is not THE
HUSBAND
I MARRIED.
THERE IS ANOTHER FORCE BEHIND
SO, INSTEAD OF FIGHTING THE MAN, FIGHT
THE POWER.
Let me just have two people because I
want to help the CHURCH TODAY.
THE DEVIL IS VERY HAPPY WHEN MEN ARE
FIGHTING EACH OTHER WITHOUT SEEING who
he is.
The day you locate the source, the
battle will end.
The problem is not mother-in-law.
That woman is an intercessor.
THE PROBLEM IS THERE IS A VOICE BEHIND
THAT WOMAN. SO, STOP CONDEMNING THE
WOMAN. Locate the real power.
AND IF YOU ARE NOT AWARE OF THE SCHEMES
AND THE DEVICES
AND THE WITTY INVENTIONS OF THE DEMONIC,
YOU'LL END UP fighting the wrong battle.
So, this is Peter.
But behind Peter
is the devil.
So, it is easy for Jesus to begin to
say,
"This man is opposing my assignment.
So, the best thing I will do, I'll put
him where he belongs.
So, I demote him from today.
You are not among the best three. In
fact, you'll enter the realm of
Bartholomew. No book will be named after
you."
How can you fight the anointed?
But, because this is the all-knowing
God, he knows the voice of Peter, and he
knows the voice of the devil.
He knows when Peter is talking, and he
knows when Lucifer is talking.
DO YOU KNOW THE VOICE NEVER ENDED UP
WITH PETER?
THIS VOICE DID NOT DIE. WHEN HE SAID,
"GET BEHIND ME, SATAN." THAT VOICE did
not die at THAT TIME. THE DEVIL still
waited for another opportune time,
because the devil wanted to know that we
are actually dealing with the right man.
AFTER IT LEFT PETER,
THE VOICE,
IT CAME IN THE CROSS.
JESUS IS ON THE CROSS.
THERE ARE TWO THIEVES.
ONE OF THEM IS THE ONE PASTOR EUGENE
SAID, "HE CAME TO STEAL,
to kill, and to destroy. THE THIEF
COMETH." THERE ARE TWO THIEVES.
WHAT SPONSORED THE SPEECH OF THAT THIEF?
"IF THOU BE THE SON OF GOD, SAVE
YOURSELF. YOU SAVED OTHERS." AND THE
OTHER ONE SAID, "I KNOW I'M HERE FOR MY
SINS, BUT I REPENT OF THEM. REMEMBER ME
IN THY KINGDOM." WHAT MADE THIS ONE
CONFESS WHAT HE CONFESSED? IT WAS THE
SAME VOICE. THE CHURCH IS DEALING with
an invisible enemy, masqueraded as
people that we know, AND WE ARE FIGHTING
THE WRONG BATTLES, BECAUSE THE SCHEMES,
THE DEVICES OF THE DEVIL ARE NOW
SHIFTING. THAT'S WHY SOMEONE SAID
"KANISA IKO NA IMAGINARY HATERS."
ONE OF THE GREATEST THINGS TODAY NI MY
HATER.
NOW SOMETIMES THE MAN YOU YOUR GREATEST
ENEMY IS THE DEVIL.
AND YOU KNOW I BEGAN TO ASK MYSELF
DO YOU KNOW WHAT THE BIBLE SAYS?
AND AND THIS ONE YOU HAVE TO BE very
careful.
Jesus
A woman is washing the feet of Jesus.
SHE'S WASHING.
PREPARING THAT IS MARY, PREPARING HIM
FOR BURIAL.
BECAUSE THE DEATH WILL BE SO URGENT
THAT THEY WILL NOT HAVE TIME TO ANOINT
HIS BODY.
SO A WOMAN CATCHES A REVELATION
AND COMES AND BEGINS TO WASH AND anoint
Jesus.
And Judas looks at THE OIL
BEING POURED.
JUDAS KNOWS THE MARKET VALUE of the oil.
It is one year's salary
wasted on the feet of Jesus. One year's
salary
poured on the feet of Jesus. Judas looks
at THAT
MANNER AND SAYS "WHAT A WASTE.
HOW CAN this woman waste oil on the feet
when the poor are in need?" And Jesus
heard the voice of Judas without
talking.
He said "The poor will be with you."
And then he looked at that woman
and said "Whatever she has done, this
one will be captured not just in time,
but even out of time.
Because these scriptures are
everlasting."
A woman.
And then he said "Not because Judas
loved the things of God, it's because he
used to help himself from the offering."
So, this is a thief
condemning a worshiper.
Can I TELL YOU A FACT IN SCRIPTURE?
MANY PEOPLE WHO don't tithe and give,
they are the most accountable concerning
church projects.
If you go and ask heaven,
"Share the giving details of this
brother."
You'll be surprised.
Judas wants to carry the offering bag,
but he does not want to contribute
to the offering bag.
But but are you getting me?
And so, the the the the the THE MAN GETS
OFFENDED.
When Jesus rebuked him, he told him,
"The poor will always be with you." When
he got rebuked, he got offended. The
enemy got an opening to convert Judas
from an apostle to a devil.
That opening is what made Judas betray
Jesus.
Because Jesus rebuked him.
AND AN OPENING BECAUSE WHAT DOES OFFENSE
DO? OFFENSE OPENS A DOOR. REMEMBER THE
DEVICES. REMEMBER THE CONTEXT OF SECOND
CORINTHIANS. IT is that IT IS A LANGUAGE
OF FORGIVENESS. AND THEN PAUL COMES AND
SAYS, "WE ARE NOT IGNORANT." The reason
why we have to forgive IS BECAUSE IF I
BEAR UNFORGIVENESS, I've I've opened a
door. And the enemy will use that door
for warfare. I CAN BECOME A WEAPON IN
THE KINGDOM OF DARKNESS, THOUGH I'M A
WORSHIPER.
DO YOU know
a man called Anton LaVey wrote and said,
"WE HAVE DISCOVERED WE CANNOT DESTROY
THE CHURCH FROM OUTSIDE."
SO, WHAT WE HAVE DISCOVERED THE BEST WAY
IS to sabotage the church from inside.
So, we don't NEED TO BRING DEVIL
WORSHIPERS IN CHURCH. WE JUST NEED TO
look accesses in the hearts of the
saints and look for what we can
capitalize them and turn Judas into a
devil.
An apostle.
Into a devil. THAT'S A THAT'S A RADICAL
TRANSITION.
ONE THAT HAS SEEN THE POWER.
ONE THAT HAS SEEN THE MIRACLES. ONE THAT
WAS AFTER IN BRIEFING PRIVATE BRIEFINGS,
BUT HE'S A DEVIL.
JESUS, when he's lifting the cup, HE
SAYS, "ONE OF YOU SHALL DIP his bread
here, but he is a devil."
So, I discovered if the devil can use
Judas,
if the devil can partner with Peter, he
can partner WITH ANYONE. MINE IS to know
this is not the sound of Elder Kanyingi.
This is not the sound of Pastor William.
This sound has AN ORIGIN. SO, WHEN I GO
TO PRAYER, I AM NOT KILLING MEN. I am
dealing with the source. You're saying,
"Oh, devil, I know your voice.
AND NOW I SILENCE you now and I declare
from this hour your operation is over.
Get behind me, SATAN." MANY PEOPLE HAVE
not understood the pattern of that
sound. We are dealing with the
wickedness of the enemy.
And that's why sometimes we we we we we
we
we become aggressive IN ATTACKING
BROTHERS, BECOME AGGRESSIVE IN
VENGEANCE, BECOME AGGRESSIVE in doing
things against others, and the devil is
very happy. He's just in a corner
laughing and saying, "If they knew I'm
the source of their trouble, they would
have attacked me."
Tell your neighbor we are not ignorant.
You can have your seats. Let's look at
Col Colossians.
Colossians.
So, THERE ARE THREE RS FOR A MAN TO WALK
IN VICTORY. THE FIRST R IS to recognize.
There are three Rs OF VICTORY. NUMBER
ONE, YOU HAVE TO RECOGNIZE. You must
recognize.
Number two, number two.
Number two, you must resist.
And number three, you have to rejoice.
When you recognize, you know what to
deploy.
Resisting is the strategy to make sure
there is no advancement. Rejoicing is
the outcome of recognizing and
resisting. So, number one, you have to
recognize.
You have to recognize that there is an
enemy. There's how he fights and there's
how he deals. Number two, we have to
resist.
Resist the devil and he will flee from
you.
So, the enemy is The enemy works with
men that do not resist. But, if a man
masters the art of resisting and
refusing, ideally, you become a
candidate of victory and that gives you
the concept of rejoicing. So, 2
Corinthians 13.
When you begin from there, it begins by
showing us When you begin from 2
Corinthians
Just give me a little bit on the
monitors. Take away my bass and put to
the highs. This will be the third time I
am 2 Corinthians 13.
2 Corinthians 13.
2 Corin- Oh, 2 Corinthians 2:13, sorry.
2 Corinthians has only four chapters.
I had no rest 2 Corinthians. Oh.
Colossians 2:13.
And you being dead in your trespasses
Is that 13?
and the uncircumcision of your flesh, he
has made our life together with him
having forgiven you all
trespasses.
This
portion of scripture
explains
the miracle of salvation.
Salvation is not the prayer that people
make.
Salvation is a divine transaction
that happens in the life of a man.
So, man has three
entities.
MAN HAS A BODY.
MAN HAS A SOUL and man has a spirit.
Man has a body.
I like what Pastor Pish taught in one of
the Thursdays. He said,
"YOU DON'T FIGHT THE FLESH. This meat
has no problem. What has a problem is
what gives life to the flesh."
Intensity of flesh.
THE PROBLEM IS THAT THAT FLESH HAS A
LIFE OF ITS OWN.
IT IS WHAT CAPACITATES THE FLESH
THAT ACTUALLY CONTROLS YOU.
AND THE LIFE OF THE FLESH IS CALLED
BIOS.
That's where we get the name biology.
Are we together?
So, SO DON'T GO AND AND AND WEIGH
YOURSELF and say, "Eh, 90 kg, I'm
struggling with the flesh. No, THAT'S
THAT'S THAT'S IN MEDICAL terms they call
it obesity.
And you can be obese and holy.
And you can be malnourished
and wicked.
SO, IT IS NOT ABOUT THE INTENSITY OF
FLESH.
IT'S ABOUT THE LIFE THAT EMPOWERS THAT
IT IS CALLED THE BIOS LIFE.
THE BIOS LIFE.
THE SECOND THING YOU HAVE, THE SOUL.
THE MIND IS IN THE SOUL.
AND THAT IS WHERE WE HAVE THE PSYCH, THE
PSYCHOLOGICAL LIFE.
SO, YOU HAVE THE BIOS AND THEN YOU HAVE
EUGENE WILL CALL it the psyche.
The psyche.
Yeah?
Psyche.
THAT'S THE LIFE OF THE SOUL.
THAT'S THE LIFE OF THE SOUL. SO, THE
PROBLEM IS NOT DEPRESSION.
THE PROBLEM IS WHO MANAGES THE LIFE of
your soul.
BECAUSE IF THE LIFE OF YOUR SOUL IS
SUBJECTED UNDER THE AUTHORITY OF CHRIST,
CASTING down every imagination,
CASTING DOWN EVERY IMAGINATION THAT
TRIES TO TELL ME I'M NOT WORTHY, I'M
USELESS, I I I DON'T DESERVE LIVING,
CASTING IT DOWN TO THE KNOWLEDGE OF
CHRIST THAT I'M MADE IN THE IMAGE OF
GOD, I'M MORE THAN A CONQUEROR, I'M A
WARRIOR, I'M VICTORIOUS, I WILL LIVE AND
NOT DIE, CASTING DOWN.
THAT IS THE BEST THERAPY you can have.
Because
every emotion can be countered by
revelation.
Every emotion can be countered by
SO, THERE IS SOMETHING THAT GIVES LIFE
TO YOUR MIND. And then now your spirit
your spirit
Now, WHEN YOU ARE NOT BORN AGAIN,
YOU HAVE A DEAD SPIRIT.
THAT'S THE REALITY.
WHEN DID THE SPIRIT OF A MAN DIE?
BECAUSE WE NEED TO UNDERSTAND THE NAME
DEATH.
DEATH THERE MEANS SEPARATED from God.
THAT'S WHAT DEATH MEANS.
SO, WHEN ADAM FELL, THE BIBLE says when
you eat of the tree, you shall surely
die.
BUT WE DON'T SEE ANY BURIAL IN EDEN.
BECAUSE THERE ARE THREE DEATHS.
There is physical death,
spiritual death, and eternal death.
There are three deaths. Physical.
Your soul and your spirit leaves the
body, and we carry the body. When people
are going for burial, YOU HEAR "MWILI
ITATOKA ke you. Mwili."
Sio Kamau. MWILI.
CUZ KAMAU LEFT.
SO, NI MWILI YA KAMAU TUMEBAKI NAYO.
NO, UTASKIA NA MWILI ITAPOKELEWA. NA
MWILI ITAZIKWA. BECAUSE THAT'S THE
PHYSICAL DEATH.
BUT YOU CAN HAVE THE BODY OF KAMAU, BUT
KAMAU IS STILL ALIVE.
SO, YOU can have physical death,
and there is ALSO SPIRITUAL DEATH.
SO, IF KAMAU DIED WITHOUT JESUS, SO YOU
HAVE THE BODY OF KAMAU DEAD, and the
spirit of Kamau dead, AND BE BECAUSE OF
THE SECOND DEATH,
NOW KAMAU HAS ENTERED ETERNAL DEATH.
THAT ETERNAL DEATH MEANS
PERMANENTLY SEPARATED FROM GOD.
SO, THERE IS NO REDEMPTION FOR KAMAU.
NO INTERCESSION CAN TAKE HIM OUT WHERE
HE IS.
SO, HE'S PERMANENTLY SEPARATED FROM GOD.
SO, there is physical death, spiritual
death, AND ETERNAL DEATH.
SO, A MAN CAN BE IN THIS SERVICE,
BREATHING, BUT THEY ARE NOT LIVING.
ACCORDING TO THE STANDARDS OF HEAVEN,
YOU ARE JUST A STATISTICS AND A VOTER,
UKO KADI, BUT HEAVEN DOES NOT EVEN
RECOGNIZE YOUR CARD.
Because you are a dead MAN WALKING.
SO, YOU ARE AND AND YOU CAN BE A MAN OF
GOOD MANNERS.
YOU CAN BE A MAN OF A STRONG WILL. YOU
HAVE DISCIPLINES.
YOU HAVE CHARACTER ATTRIBUTES, BUT YOU
DON'T HAVE LIFE.
SO, WHAT HAPPENS? SO, IF A MAN IS DEAD,
IF YOU HAVE A DEAD SPIRIT, YOU DON'T
NEED RESUSCITATION.
YOU NEED RESURRECTION.
THE MEDICAL TERM, YOU KNOW, I USED TO
LOVE MOVIES.
AND A MAN WILL BE SHOT,
THE STARRING WILL BE SHOT.
AND ONCE HE'S SHOT, THE AMBULANCE COMES,
THEY TAKE HIM, THEY CHECK THE PULSE, AND
they say, "The man IS STILL ALIVE. THE
HEART IS STILL BEATING." THEN THEY TAKE
HIM TO HTU, and they PUT ALL THESE
MACHINES. THEN SUDDENLY AN ALARM RINGS,
AND YOU SEE A FLAT LINE. AND YOU SEE A
DOCTOR WITH THOSE THINGS, RESUSCITATION
MACHINES, AND THEY WILL PUT ON HIS
CHEST, AND YOU SEE a boof. AND IF YOU
ARE IF YOU LOVE ACTION MOVIES, YOU KNOW,
A STARRING CANNOT DIE.
BECAUSE AS I COULD GO FOR MOVIE MISSION,
THEN THE MAN WILL DO IT AGAIN, THEN YOU
HEAR BOOF, AND THEN AGAIN BOOF, AND THEN
YOU SEE THE LINE GOING, AND YOU KNOW, MY
GUY IS AROUND. HE CANNOT DIE. YOU DON'T
DON'T DIE IN THE MOVIE YOU'RE ACTING.
YOU KNOW, SOME OF US USED TO WRITE
COMPOSITION. THE DAY I'LL NEVER FORGET,
AND THEN YOU DIE IN THAT DAY, AND THE
TEACHER WILL COME AND ASK YOU, "HOW DID
YOU HOW DID YOU FINISH THE COMPOSITION?"
TELL YOUR NEIGHBOR, "DON'T DIE IN YOUR
STORY.
AND SO WHAT HAPPENS IS THAT A DEAD MAN
DOES NOT NEED WHAT? RESUSCITATION. A
DEAD MAN NEEDS RESURRECTION.
SO WHAT JESUS CAME, WE NEED TO
UNDERSTAND THAT GOD IS A SPIRIT.
GOD IS A SPIRIT.
AND THE SPIRIT OF GOD is eternal.
THE SPIRIT OF GOD HAS NO TIME. IT
DOESN'T IT IS NOT PHRASED OR LIMITED IN
THE PARAMETERS OF TIME.
THE SPIRIT OF GOD IS ETERNAL.
THE SPIRIT OF GOD CARRIES THE LIFE OF
GOD.
GOD. THE LIFE OF GOD IS CALLED ZOE.
NOW, LET ME HAVE TWO PEOPLE, PLEASE.
LET me show you what happens.
Or let me have three people so that I
can explain. Pastor Ronnie, come now
because you're standing. Now, stand
there because now I know I'm teaching.
Come, I need three people. Three.
So
We have the flesh, we have the soul, we
have the spirit.
So this is the flesh.
Stand in front. So this is the flesh.
Flesh is always big. We take care of the
flesh.
IT'S PERPETUALLY DEMANDING.
IT THIS ONE
IF YOU FOCUS ON this one, it will
demand. Then we have the soul. That's
the mind.
Then we have the spirit. Now, we have
people who have perfected the physical
LIFE AND THEIR BIOS IS OKAY.
They They They go for vitals, checkups,
blood. Everything is okay. They are
living and breathing. They are happy.
They are They are considered healthy.
Then there ARE PEOPLE WHO ARE NOW
MASTERS OF THERAPY. I CHECK my mind. I
don't allow negative energies, auras, to
affect me. I observe my space. My peace
is paramount. We bless God for you.
BUT YOU MIGHT BE OKAY BIOLOGICALLY,
OKAY PSYCHOLOGICALLY, BUT DEAD
SPIRITUALLY.
WHEN GOD IS AUDITING MEN, HE DOES NOT
LOOK YOU FROM THIS LEVEL. HE LOOKS FROM
THE SPIRIT.
SO, A MAN CAN BE OKAY IN THE EYES OF THE
PROPHET, BUT ACCORDING TO HEAVEN, THAT
IS NOT THE MAN.
BECAUSE YOU KNOW, DAVID ENCOUNTERED THE
SPIRIT OF GOD. FOR DAVID TO SAY, "LET
THY HOLY SPIRIT NOT DEPART FROM ME." IT
MEANS THE MAN ABODE IN THE HOLY GHOST.
THAT'S WHY SAMUEL COMES. HE'S LOOKING AT
THE BROTHERS. THEY ARE OKAY IN THE BIOS,
OKAY PSYCHOLOGICALLY, BUT DEAD
SPIRITUALLY. THEY CANNOT fulfill any
KINGDOM ASSIGNMENT.
THEY ARE THEY THESE ARE THESE ARE
MILITARY MEN. THEY ARE GRADUATES. THEY
HAVE THE ACCOLADES. THEY ARE CVS ARE
OKAY, BUT THE STANDARDS OF HEAVEN HAS
NOT YET BEEN MET.
AND THAT'S WHY THE BIBLE SAYS GOD IS NOT
A RESPECTER OF MAN, BECAUSE MAN HAS
STANDARDS AND GOD HAS HIS STANDARDS. GOD
CANNOT LOWER HIS STANDARDS to
accommodate man. WHEN HE SAYS HE'S NOT A
RESPECTER OF MEN, IT MEANS GOD WILL
BYPASS WHAT MAN HAS QUALIFIED to lift
what he has qualified.
So, the Lord is more concerned about
your spirit.
So, if this man dies, we will bury the
body.
And the spirit will be separated to go
to hell, eternally separated from God.
Because to to dust you came,
to dust you return. That's where we end.
But from spirit you came.
But returning to the spirit, if you are
dead, this spirit cannot commune with a
dead spirit.
So, this is the transaction of the
grave, but there is another deeper
transaction.
So, this man is in Life Church today,
looking sharp as this man, but no matter
how well-groomed you are, you are dead.
Even if you are buried in a golden
coffin, mighty mighty.
You know, when Alexander the Great died,
he wrote a very sad eulogy.
You study Alexander the Great. THAT'S
WHY HE'S CALLED THE GREAT. That's where
the name the goat came from.
Alexander the Great,
before 30 years, he had conquered the
whole of the Persian Empire.
That was a young man.
CONQUERED EVERYTHING. UNTIL MEN BEGAN TO
WRITE MYTHS about him, and they said he
was half god, HALF MAN.
THOUGH DANIEL HAD PROPHESIED ABOUT the
Greek civilization. SO, THE MAN DIED AT
AROUND 33 years old, 30-33 there.
And before he died, in his eulogy, he
said, "Number one, my grave, my coffin,
should be carried by the best of doctors
in the Greek territory. Number two, on
the PATHWAY TO MY GRAVE, LAY IT with
gold.
And number three, let the coffin be
open, so that both of my arms can be
seen in the whole of the territory. This
is the greatest general, according to
history, that has ever lived. And he
said the reason why he wanted to say
that is because people believed the man
died out of malaria. And he was TRYING
TO EXPLAIN "NO AMOUNT OF POWER, NO
AMOUNT OF medical
you know, knowledge can save a man from
death."
THE GREEKS PIONEERED THE CIVILIZATION of
medicine Ali. Dr. EDWIN IS HERE. MOST OF
THE THINGS we study in medicine came
from the Greeks. Both spiritual and
NATURAL MEDICINE HAS ORIGIN FROM THE
GREEK, BUT THEY COULD not deliver a KING
AND A MAN THAT TO ONE IN ALL BATTLES,
BUT NEVER WON IN THE battle of death.
That's the mystery of life.
He said, "When I die, let my coffin be
carried by the finest of doctors as a
reminder that no man has power over
death. LET THEM LAY ALL MY WEALTH ON THE
GROUND TO SHOW MEN THE FUTILITY of
wealth when it comes to health."
And let me die
with my arms open
to show men how useless we are when
death comes and empty we came, empty we
shall return.
I read it because I thought it was a
myth. SO, I WENT AND RESEARCHED IT WAS
THIS AND I realized actually those were
the words of Alexander the Great.
So, this is a believer today.
He's in life church
or online.
Because God is not moved by your suit
and your cologne.
You don't put designer cologne to take
away the stench of sin.
And so, this man comes
and he makes a prayer that we make
casually.
So, Jesus is seated.
That's it.
And when the man is walking on the
altar, he believes
that actually Jesus died on the cross
for my sins.
And he comes and meet Pastor T and we
tell him, "Lift up your hands. Say I'm a
sinner in need of a savior." When Jesus
hears in need of a savior, HE WAKES UP.
BECAUSE FINALLY SOMEONE HAS acknowledged
that he has a dead spirit.
And today I now invite him, "Come." I
now invite him. We don't see this drama,
but this is what happens. I now invite
him into my life. Jesus begins to come
because God, Jesus, and the Holy Ghost,
they are the same. He's the spirit. He
begins to come. Guess what happens? He
does not jump in the flesh. He does not
jump in the mind. He now comes to the
spirit.
THAT'S WHY SOMETIMES YOU FEEL NOTHING
because it's not a feeling.
THE FLESH DOES NOT BECOME BLUE.
NOTHING CHANGES.
IF YOU HAD DREADLOCKS, THEY ARE STILL
THERE. IF YOU WERE SMELLING ALCOHOL, THE
SMELL IS STILL THERE.
NOTHING CHANGES PHYSICALLY.
NOTHING CHANGES FIRST PSYCHOLOGICALLY,
BUT THE GREATEST MIRACLE HAS HAPPENED
SPIRITUALLY THAT NOW THE DEAD SPIRIT
NOW, THIS IS WHAT WE DON'T SEE.
THIS SPIRIT WAS DEAD. DIE. SIT DOWN.
THIS SPIRIT WAS DEAD.
NATURALLY, WHEN NOW THE SPIRIT OF GOD
COMES, LISTEN, IT IT NOW PARTNERS WITH
YOUR SPIRIT AND THE LIFE OF THE SPIRIT
OF GOD BECOMES THE LIFE OF YOUR DEAD
SPIRIT BECAUSE THE spirit of God is THE
SPIRIT OF RESURRECTION.
SO, WHERE OUR DEATH HAS REIGNED,
RESURRECTION POWER HAS ENTERED. SO, YOUR
SPIRIT IS NOW ALIVE. WHAT GAVE IT THE
POWER? IT IS THE SPIRIT OF GOD. WHAT IS
THE SPIRIT OF GOD? IT IS AN ETERNAL
SPIRIT. SO, AUTOMATICALLY, YOU HAVE
RECEIVED ETERNAL LIFE.
BECAUSE WHAT GIVES THE FLESH THE LIFE,
THE BIOS? WHAT GIVES THE MIND THE
PSYCHOLOGY, THE PSYCHE LIFE? SO, YOUR
SPIRIT NEEDS A LIFE. IT COMES FROM THE
SPIRIT OF GOD. AND SUDDENLY, YOU HAVE AN
ETERNAL LIFE. YOU HAVE NOW THE LIFE OF
GOD IN YOUR SPIRIT. SO, NOW THIS LIFE IS
CALLED ZOE.
THE LIFE OF GOD IS IN YOUR SPIRIT. NOW,
NOTHING HAS HAPPENED TO YOUR FLESH.
NOTHING HAS HAPPENED TO YOUR MIND, BUT
THE GREATEST MIRACLE HAS happened in
YOUR SPIRIT. THE LIFE OF GOD HAS JUST
ENTERED. THAT'S WHY THE BIBLE SAYS, "AND
THE SPIRIT THAT RAISED JESUS FROM THE
DEAD, THAT VERY SPIRIT IS THE ONE THAT
LIFTS US NOW."
YOU SEE, WE WE BECOME CASUAL WITH THIS
SALVATION BECAUSE WE DON'T understand
the transaction.
People are waiting for cripples TO WALK.
A DEAD HAS NO VALUE IN ETERNITY.
BECAUSE A WHO WILL NOT ENTER
GLORY IS WASTAGE OF POWER.
A BLIND MAN THAT SEES WITHOUT SALVATION
IS USELESS. A MAN TODAY, POSSIBLY
SUFFERING FROM CANCER STAGE FOUR IN HDU,
HEALED WITHOUT THE CROSS, THAT MAN IS
USELESS.
NOW, OUR DEMAND IS ON THE POWER, BUT NOT
THE POWER THAT CAN SAVE.
AND MIRACLES ARE SUPPOSED TO CHALLENGE
YOUR MIND.
SO, THAT YOU CAN SURRENDER YOUR HEART.
MIRACLES IS NOT THE CURRENCY FOR
BUILDING POWERFUL PASTORS.
IT IS WHAT BREAKS HARD GROUNDS.
Because there are men who have THE HEART
OF PHARAOH. THEY must see miracles
for them to believe there is a God. SO,
THE LORD WILL USE THE POWER TO BREAK
THEIR HEART AND MAKE IT FOLLOW SO THAT A
DOCTOR WHO IS A WHO IS A DOCTOR THAT
OPERATES WITH MATTERS EYE SEES A BLIND
MAN SEE AND HE CONFIRMS HE WAS BLIND.
THE THE THE THE THE THE CONCEPT OF THE
EYE EVERYTHING WAS DEAD. THAT DOCTOR
WILL NOW SAY, "I BELIEVE there is a God
in heaven because this has challenged my
philosophies."
And even that blind man after seeing,
the next thing is, "Are you born again?"
Same up. Born again.
Your eyes are not as important as your
soul.
Am I speaking to anyone?
Now, this is what happens. This
life of God
If you're BORN AGAIN, YOU HAVE THIS
LIFE.
IT IS CALLED ZOE.
NOW, LISTEN. THIS IS WHAT HAPPENS.
It is possible to have something, but
you don't know.
So, come back.
So, THIS IS THIS IS WHAT HAPPENS.
These are the believers. They come to
church. They are good givers. They are
good tithes.
But, they have never known what they
have.
So, what makes them become casual and
live a casual life, there is no identity
of who they are in Christ.
This identity
this realization is what gives you
victory even over certain matters.
If today files were to be removed
and then you suspect
possibly you are one of the sons
of Daniel Toroitich Arap Moi the late.
You just summon a lawyer just comes and
says,
"Ah, it's like
the late president was your father. I
know your mother is a single mother, but
it's like your mother also died. We
found these documents and it looks like
you are
the late president's son.
And he has left a will and there are
things that need to be given to you.
Even if you are living in a bedsitter,
the day you the way you will go back to
THAT BEDSITTER, HI.
HE'S OUT IN AFRICA EDITION. LISTEN, YOUR
ACCOUNT HAS NOT CHANGED.
YOUR HOUSE HAS NOT CHANGED, BUT THERE IS
A REVELATION THAT I COULD HAVE ANOTHER
IDENTITY OTHER THAN WHAT I HAVE. YOU
WILL GO AND SEE YOURSELF IN THE MIRROR
AND REALIZE NOT GOING TO COME HANDSOME.
IN A POOR COUPLE, SEE DEFAULT SETTING.
THESE ARE THE PARAMETERS OF A HANDSOME
MAN.
BUT NOW, BECAUSE YOU DON'T KNOW WHO YOU
ARE, WHATEVER THE DEVIL THROWS AT YOU,
YOU BELIEVE IT. WHATEVER THEY SAW, YOU
BELIEVE IT. WHEN YOU GET TO KNOW WHO YOU
ARE, THERE ARE CERTAIN BATTLES THAT END
AUTOMATICALLY.
IDENTITY
IS A VERY POWERFUL THING.
I don't know why. HAVE YOU REALIZED RICH
MEN DON'T TRY TO LOOK RICH?
POOR MEN STRUGGLE TO BE POOR.
POOR MEN ARE THE ONES WHO WORK SO HARD
TO LOOK RICH.
I never saw Chris Kirubi on Instagram
doing his daily routine.
I've just woken up.
Today I think I'll take my Bentley.
He's a poor young man
with a Mazda Demio on loan
who cannot make Kenyans sleep.
We even know when you're sleeping.
The kind of wrath
because they have touched your
inheritance, life savings.
Everything you ever had is on this car.
Now I'm so angry that you are going to
be in a medical scratch.
Okay, what about Mazda Cena Obaya?
You better not
make this a personal me example. I don't
know me Nico about one me Liam Bua come
up on a garden on a young woman Probox
Kenya in Mazda Demio and my police. So
we got out. So on Sunday to Kenya Nico
put a Zimmer Pango.
Do you know what is in A BIG WAR AS IN a
license is on the Probox?
But one but I hope you get the point. I
have no problem with Mazda Demio. If
you're a driver, please we see to be
back home Kenya. So I was in a comma.
I'm just giving an example. Now listen,
this is the miracle that happened. Are
you understanding? Are you and you being
dead in your trespasses and the
uncircumcision of your flesh, he has
made alive together with him HAVING
FORGIVEN YOU ALL
TRESPASSES.
WHAT IS TO TRESPASS? IS THERE A
BOUNDARIES THAT HAVE BEEN SET, BUT
BECAUSE THE LIFE OF THE FLESH IS
STRONGER THAN THE LIFE OF THE SPIRIT,
you keep on going BEYOND THE SET
BOUNDARIES. SO THE LORD NOT ONLY HAS HE
GIVEN YOU ANOTHER LIFE, HE HAS ALSO
TAKEN AWAY EVERYTHING YOU HAD EVER DONE.
BECAUSE BEFORE THE LIFE CAME,
YOU HAD THE LIFE THAT RULED YOUR LIFE,
WHICH IS THE FLESH.
SO THE LORD CANNOT CONDEMN YOU FOR WHAT
YOU DID before the life.
So there is a difference when a believer
sins
and a non-believer sins.
Because one has no life. The other one
has the life.
And and and now
what we do
is
we can never teach the spirit
what it has received.
SO, WE BEGIN NOW TO TEACH THE MIND
WHAT
THIS BODY has received. Yes.
Thank you.
Romans chapter number 12
and verse one.
That's why you are writing notes.
Otherwise, if this was a spiritual
encounter
we would have thrown spiritual books
into your spirit.
And we tell you bring thanks for 1 hour
and you download the system.
The Bible says, everybody read. I
beseech you therefore brethren by the
mercies of God that you present your
bodies a living sacrifice holy
acceptable to God, which is your
reasonable
So, Paul is not writing to unbelievers.
And you have to understand who Paul is
writing to, brethren. Who are brethren?
Those who are born again. But you have
to understand that Paul he Paul has gone
beyond the bios.
You can't tell the bios to bring itself
on the altar.
The audience of this scripture is not
the flesh.
There is a man Paul is addressing.
And that man is not the natural man.
Cuz you can either be natural, carnal,
or spiritual. It's either or dead.
Natural, carnal, or spiritual. So, I
beseech you therefore brethren by the
mercies of God that you present your
bodies. So, the body must be under what
is being instructed.
So, there is something that can carry
the body.
There is something in man that can carry
the body and suspend the life of the
body and make the body lie on an altar
not as a dead but as a living sacrifice
and receive the POWER AND THE FIRE OF
THE ALTAR without running.
I'm going slowly.
Because he's saying
This is your holy acceptable to God
which is your reasonable service. What
Paul is trying to say
if you're a true brethren it means the
order have shifted. It is no longer the
flesh that leads you. It is the spirit.
The soul.
The body.
So Paul is not writing. When you're
writing to the brethren, you are
addressing the spirit and the soul. I
beseech you therefore brethren that
that you bring that body to the altar as
a living sacrifice. That means the body
has not conquered the spirit.
You cannot surrender what you have not
conquered.
Let me come to your level.
There are certain amounts of giving you
can never give
because you have not conquered that
level.
It is true.
In us. That means that level has
conquered you.
So the Lord is saying there are must be
a conquering.
So that now we no longer know you after
the flesh.
We now know no man after the flesh. We
now begin TO KNOW YOU NOT AFTER THE dead
spirit but after the resurrected spirit.
And this man is a mystery.
So, the moment you are having beef with
this man, you are having beef with God.
Paul, Paul, why thou persecuted I? Who,
Lord? I. No, I'm killing believers. That
is me because I am in them.
So, if I hate a believer, I'm not
hitting a man. I'm hitting God.
AND THAT'S WHY I HAVE NO POWER TO JUDGE
A BELIEVER.
I can judge an unbeliever.
I can judge actions according to
standards of scripture, but I have no
authority to judge God in a man.
I have taken the place of God. He's too
high.
That's why there are things that happen
and I say, "I'll pray for you."
Because my utterance in that matter may
not matter.
So, this is how God views us.
Are you understanding up to there?
So, this is how God views us and this is
the order.
For are we together?
For are we there?
Singles, are you there?
Let me tell you why relationships don't
last.
It's because you always meet like this.
I love my brother. You look for side
burns.
Biceps,
flesh.
So, you have a MAN THAT HAS EVERYTHING
in the flesh, but he's dead in the
spirit. He can't hear God.
He can't pick instructions concerning
eternity. So, what you dragged in
marriage is A BODY.
ONE DAY, YOU WILL NEED DIRECTION IN THE
SPIRIT. If this body cannot hear God,
you're in trouble.
And that's WHY IN THE NATURAL EYES THIS
MAN MAY LOOK OKAY. IN THE WHEN YOU BEGIN
TO TELL GOD, "SHOW ME WHO THIS MAN IS."
HE WILL SHOW YOU A COFFIN.
But if you don't say amen.
"SHOW ME WHO THIS SISTER IS." HE WILL
SHOW YOU A COFFIN.
SHE HAS EVERYTHING IN THE RIGHT PLACE,
FINGERTIPS, HIPS, EYES, RIGHT COLOR,
EVERYTHING. COFFIN.
BECAUSE I DON'T GO FOR APPEARANCE, I GO
FOR RESURRECTION.
SO BY THE TIME I SEE A MAN IN THE SPIRIT
AND I KNOW WHO THEY ARE, THEN THAT GIVES
ME ADVANTAGE.
There are people even in church I've
been telling the Lord, "Show me who this
person is."
Not because they are wicked, because I
could be missing on a reality that they
carry.
And God begins to open MY EYES. SO, WHEN
YOU GO TO DATE, say you look good, say I
love you. I say advance, God bless you.
And then you tell the Holy Ghost, "Show
me the man
in the spirit.
If he's NOT WEARING A WHITE SUIT,
JUST TELL HIM, "BRO, thank you for
lunch."
I I And that's why we have body counts.
Hallelujah. That's why you have
body counts. Because the name body
counts is a language of dead bodies that
have been counted waiting to go to
mortuary.
And they are put in black paper bags.
So, you'll hear they are were you I
don't know why they always say there
were three Americans and 70 Kenyans. You
know, it's so
A body is a body, whether it's a Russian
man or a Kenyan man a
A body is a body.
Mighty in mighty.
I beseech you therefore. Now, look at
the second one. I'm I'm finishing now.
Are you enjoying?
I know you are not touching the message
of today.
This scripture to me pop up before we
figure out Colossians 15. Because up 15
you don't begin in the middle of a
sentence.
Now let's all read and do not be
Do not be
So
You can have a regenerated spirit.
But you do not have a delivered mind.
What happens?
The spirit is resurrected.
The mind is delivered. The body is
disciplined.
Are you seeing in this body?
It does not flow with anointing oil.
Here I have blood.
It has hemoglobin.
Red and white blood cells.
It has hormones.
I feel what people feel.
But when the mind is delivered, it's
very easy to discipline
the body.
And guess what? God will not kill this
body.
I know people always say I kill my
flesh.
Please don't.
Don't declare death.
WHAT WILL HAPPEN? BY the life of the
spirit
The life of the spirit has the ability
to affect your soul and to affect your
body. Because the Bible says this life
gives vitality
to our mortal bodies.
It gives THERE IS AN EMPOWERMENT THAT
CAN COME FROM THE SPIRIT TO THE BODY.
THAT EMPOWERMENT SOMETIMES IS WHAT kills
diseases.
What was the scripture in Romans? I know
you know it.
Romans 8 and verse 11.
Go there. Romans 8:11. But if the spirit
of him
who raised Jesus from the dead, what
does he do?
DWELLS, NOT VISIT, NOT ENCOUNTER, NOT
VISITATION, DWELLING. SO, AS YOU AS YOU
WALK OUT TO YOUR CAR, HE'S IN YOU.
AS YOU GO TO YOUR WORK, HE'S IN YOU. YOU
DON'T COME TO MEET HIM ON SUNDAY. HE'S
IN YOU. HE DWELLS.
WHICH spirit that raised Jesus FROM THE
DEAD? WHAT IS THAT SPIRIT? THE SPIRIT OF
RESURRECTION. SO, IF THAT SPIRIT IS IN
YOU, NOTHING CAN DIE IN YOU.
In you, HE WHO RAISED CHRIST FROM THE
DEAD WILL ALSO GIVE LIFE TO YOUR MORTAL
BODIES
THROUGH HIS spirit who dwells in You can
see the dwelling. Give me this in NLT
and Message Bible. We read and then we
share that and then we pray.
TPT
IT STANDS TO REASON, DOESN'T IT, THAT IF
THEY'RE ALIVE LET US READ.
It's You know, someone told me I was
asked, "Why is it that the opposition
love coming to church to fight the
president?" And the man said a very
powerful thing. He said, "You know the
church is the only custodian of truth.
And the only place where the opposition
can say the truth is in church, because
in parliament all parliamentarians have
been bought." I said, "I've never seen
it this way."
Said the politicians can even
"When I tell you when God anointed
David, he was the soul, he was the
chosen one. So
he was the chosen one."
Now
I can SAY I'M NO LONGER with him. So
they said, "The answer is a politician
PREACHING." SAYING, "DON'T FIGHT THE
CHURCH."
THESE MEN ARE LOADED.
SO EVEN AS WE HAVE TO SHOUT, tell your
neighbor where we
So let's read. It It stands to reason,
doesn't it, that if THE ALIVE AND
PRESENT GOD, WHO RAISED JESUS from the
dead, moves into your life, he will do
the same thing in you that he did in
Jesus, bringing you alive TO HIMSELF.
WHEN GOD LIVES and breathes in you, AND
HE DOES AS SURELY AS HE DID IN JESUS,
YOU ARE DELIVERED FROM THAT DEAD LIFE
WITH HIS spirit living IN YOU. YOUR BODY
WILL BE AS ALIVE
SO WHEN WHEN WHEN OH MY GOD. SO WHEN
WHEN WHEN THE SPIRIT IS IN YOU, YOU NOW
POSSESS A BODY LIKE THAT OF JESUS.
BECAUSE JESUS HAD THE BODY OF A MAN, BUT
WHATEVER GAVE HIM ADVANTAGE IS WHEN THE
HOLY GHOST CAME UPON THAT BODY, AND
SOMETHING BEGAN TO HAPPEN. THAT BODY
COULD NOT BE TEMPTED SEXUALLY. THAT BODY
THE APPETITES OF THE BODY WERE NOW
SUBJECTED UNDER THE AUTHORITY AND THE
APPETITES OF HEAVEN. THAT BODY COULD
PRAY FOR A WHOLE NIGHT. THAT BODY COULD
FAST. THAT BODY COULD SEEK THE POWER AND
THE PRESENCE OF GOD. THAT BODY SOUGHT
THE THINGS OF THE FIRE. HALLELUJAH. THE
SPIRIT DWELLS IN YOU.
HE'S IN YOU.
IT'S ONLY THAT YOU DIDN'T KNOW SOME OF
THESE THINGS.
LET'S GO BACK NOW TO
COLOSSIANS.
NO, ROMANS.
12:2
cuz I want to show you something.
It starts to reason, oh my God.
Do not conform to this world, this age,
fashioned after and adapted to its
external, superficial customs.
But be transformed, changed by the
entire renewal of your mind by its new
ideas and its new attitude. Hold it
there. Hold it there.
Read it again.
Read
Do not be conformed to this world, this
age.
It time of our mama, time of our papa.
DO NOT BE CONFORMED
TO THIS WORLD, THIS AGE,
FASHIONED AFTER
AND ADAPTED TO ITS EXTERNAL,
SUPERFICIAL. THEY ARE NOT PERMANENT.
THEY ARE THEY LOOK GOOD, BUT they are
superficial customs.
BUT BE TRANSFORMED. WHAT IS TO
TRANSFORM? CHANGED BY THE ENTIRE, NOT
JUST PART, THE ENTIRE RENEWAL OF YOUR
MIND. WHAT DOES THAT MEAN? THERE HAS TO
BE NEW IDEAS and its new attitudes. HOW
YOU INTERACT WITH PEOPLE, HOW YOU TALK
TO PEOPLE. BY THE TIME PEOPLE SEE YOU,
YOU DON'T NEED TO TELL THEM YOU ARE BORN
AGAIN. THEY CAN SEE THERE IS another
attitude. THIS MAN CAN LOVE SOMEONE THAT
OFFENDED THEM. THIS MAN CAN GIVE THE
OTHER CHEEK BECAUSE THEY slapped you on
this OTHER CHEEK. THIS MAN CARRIES A
CERTAIN ATMOSPHERE. MANY believers we
have failed in this.
IN FACT, CHRISTIANITY A JACKET.
DO NOT GO OUT OF THE WORLD IN THE NAME
OF WE NEED TO be wise.
Then Sunday WE BECOME SPIRITUAL. THAT'S
WHY THERE ARE NO RESULTS IN THE
MARKETPLACE.
BECAUSE IF YOU CANNOT APPLY the Bible in
the business, if you cannot apply the
Bible in your career, if you cannot
APPLY THE BIBLE WHERE YOU ARE TO YOUR
CHILDREN, THEN YOU ARE NOT A BELIEVER,
YOU ARE A RELIGIOUS PHARISEE AND
SADDUCEE.
OBSERVER OF THE LAW, LOOKING AT HOW
PEOPLE ARE NOT KEEPING THE LAW, YOU ARE
A DEAD WHITEWASHED TOMB. YOU ARE CLEAN
OUTSIDE BUT DEAD INSIDE.
YOU ARE LIKE A THERMOS THAT CARRIES DEAD
FOOD BUT IT IS CLEAN OUTSIDE. THOSE ARE
THE WORDS OF JESUS. OF COURSE, I'VE GOT
TO TELL YOU THAT I'm a soul.
THE GREATEST TEST OF YOUR FAITH IS NOT
RECITATION OF SCRIPTURE.
ATTENDING PRAYER. THE GREATEST TEST OF
YOUR FAITH IS NOT BEING IN A FAMILY
GROUP, IS LIVING THE WORD OF GOD.
THAT'S THE GREATEST TEST.
WE WILL NOT BE JUDGED BY ACTIVITIES, WE
WILL BE JUDGED BY CONFORMITY.
AS HE IS, SO WE ARE.
JESUS WILL KNOW WHO ARE HIS BECAUSE THEY
LOOK LIKE HIM.
SO, ANYONE THAT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE HIM,
IT HE IS NOT
HIS.
And this
My workplace, how are we?
People, how are we in our workplace?
THAT'S WHERE THE TESTIMONIES
I'VE GOT TO DO
>> YOU SHOULD HAVE CALLED ME SUNDAY.
I will know your
by your house help.
We don't just hear it.
We live it.
We become it.
That you can look at someone
worthy of judgement and the Lord tells
you extend mercy.
Worthy because my nature. Can I give you
a very simple formula of living?
Before you do anything, always ask
yourself what would Jesus have done?
Simple. It will carry you a long way.
Because if the spirit
gives you the body like of Christ
then he has to give you the speech of
Christ. The mind of Christ.
>> That could be said YOU CAN SPEAK YOUR
MIND.
And then you ask yourself, what would
Jesus have done
in this situation?
A woman caught
in the very act.
You know, that's that's so
not just scandalous, but very graphical.
I don't know what those men were doing.
DON'T KNOW HOW THEY knew there was an
act happening.
So, they have to disrupt THE ACT
AND SAY, "COME."
AND WE DON'T KNOW WHERE THE MAN WAS.
IT WAS THE CULTURE BECAUSE women in
those cultures were
it was it was a little bit bad.
AND THEY BRING SO, WE HAVE EVIDENCE.
WE HAVE NOT HEARD. WE ARE EYEWITNESSES.
THE MAN, THAT MAN, WE KNOW HIM.
WE KNOW HIM.
And Jesus, the Bible says,
he never spoke to them.
He went down
and began to write.
Then he said,
"He that has no sin,
let him be the first
to cast a stone
to that woman."
And you know the Bible says, as he was
writing, they had
We don't know what he wrote.
And the Bible says,
they left
one by one from the oldest.
And I want to believe
So, they were part of that company of
sleeping with prostitutes.
And they are here trying to test who
Jesus is.
The Bible says they left one by one.
Today as a leader,
a woman is a brother is brought to you.
Maybe not caught from the very act.
But a brother comes and tells you,
"Sister so-and-so
is going through one to three."
What will you do?
What will Jesus
do?
You know, sometimes I see it as a
manager, I see it as a employer.
And sometimes I'm blamed for being a
pastor.
But I keep on saying, "What will Jesus
do in that situation?"
That has been my principle in life.
That There are two things I was taught
when I was young, that Jesus sees.
Whether you're under the bed, under the
shoe, he sees. You remember those
stories?
And they they they have kept you.
Cuz my my my my Sunday school teacher
was very dramatic. At the end of the
journey, he had to go to the future. My
mom and them
So, I eat stuck with me up to date.
What will Jesus do?
Tell your neighbor, "That's the mantra
that will keep you
walking in faithfulness." Let's finish.
Let's finish.
So, what happens to the mind?
The mind is
The mind is renewed and it is
transformed. That is why
it is important to teach this word
because people's mind begin to change.
Are you getting it?
And what happens when your mind change?
Your perspective changes. Your attitude
changes. Your ideas changes and your
behavior changes.
So, you can't change a man before you
change his mind.
True transformation is not in encounter.
True transformation is in
the mind deliverance.
We can't change how you see yourself
until we change what you know about
yourself.
We can't change some of the things.
Some of us we we used to love alcohol.
And I'll tell you for free.
It is true.
What do you do with it?
Without a cause.
But listen.
When
understanding came
that my body is the temple of the HOLY
SPIRIT. WHEN UNDERSTANDING CAME THAT
SECULAR music carries secular and
DEMONIC SPIRITS. WHEN UNDERSTANDING CAME
THAT I SHOULD NOT BE DRUNK of wine or
any strong drink, BUT BE DRUNK OF THE
HOLY GHOST. THAT UNDERSTANDING BEGAN TO
MODERATE our appetites.
IT IS THAT UNDERSTANDING THAT CHANGES
HOW A man behaves.
And that's why we teach the word. So,
what happens? The spirit is
resuscitated.
The mind is delivered. The body is
disciplined.
And this discipline is a daily walk.
The Bible says, "I crucify my flesh
daily."
Not one day.
This is the secret of freedom. When you
wake up, you don't just open your eyes.
Your flesh has also woken up.
So, everything in that body will begin
to react. SO, YOU MUST REMEMBER YOU HAVE
A responsibility to crucify the body and
allow the spirit to lead you cuz then
that are led of the spirit are sons of
God. And it is not an easy affair
BECAUSE THERE ARE ENOUGH TIMES when the
body wants to take control, enough
times. And that's WHY IT'S VERY POWERFUL
WHEN YOU WAKE UP, whatever you listen,
whatever jump starts your life matters a
lot.
BY THE TIME YOU WAKE UP, ATMOSPHERE HAS
SHIFTED. You need to wake UP IN TONGUES.
BECAUSE MY MAGIC OF A body doesn't have
a thing to do WITH A FIRE. HOLY Ghost
fire versus cold water.
There is comfort in home
warm water. When I pick UP BY THE TIME
YOU DISCOVER YOU HAVE PROGRAMMED your
day in the spirit, your spirit HAS TAKEN
OVER. SO, WHATEVER THE devil presents,
you are able to edit. You know this is
not of God. This is not how I'm supposed
to behave because your spirit is lifted.
THE SONGS, THE WORD. WHAT IS THE
ATMOSPHERE IN YOUR CAR? WHAT DOES IT DO
TO THE SUBWAY?
Are we together?
And so, the mind, that's why we preach.
And we will preach until the mind
changes, until you begin to see like
God. Let this mind that was IN CHRIST
JESUS. LET THIS MIND BE IN YOU. SO, YOU
DON'T JUST NEED THE BODY OF JESUS AND
THE spirit of Jesus, YOU ALSO NEED THE
MIND OF CHRIST.
SO, THAT WHEN YOU ARE WALKING ON EARTH,
YOU ARE ALSO A SON OF GOD. BECAUSE THEN
THAT BELIEVE HE GAVE THEM THE POWER TO
BECOME THE SONS OF GOD. WHO IS THIS?
THIS IS MY SON WITH WHOM I'M WELL
PLEASED WITH. SO, THAT'S WHAT THE LORD
SAID ABOUT JESUS. SO, WHEN I WALK ON
EARTH, I AM A SON OF GOD. WHO IS A SON
OF GOD? JESUS MODELED HOW SONS OPERATE.
SO, I see like Jesus. I love like Jesus.
I forgive like Jesus. I rebuke like
Jesus. I live like Jesus and I manifest
like Jesus.
It is good for me to go so that he may
come.
A seed abideth in nothing when it
abideth alone. So, we are
Christ-like.
We are Christ-like.
This is the Christ consciousness.
It is new attitude so that you may prove
for yourselves what is the good and
acceptable and perfect will of God. Even
the thing which is good and acceptable
and perfect in his sight for you. This
is now the perfection of the work.
Go back to the scriptures. I receive the
worshipers. Thank you.
Colossians 2.
My notes are still here.
The weapons of our warfare.
Seven of them.
That is
having canceled and blotted out and
wiped away the handwriting of the note.
And you who were dead in trespass and in
the uncircumcision of your flesh,
your sensuality, your sinful carnal
nature, God brought to life together
with Christ, having freely forgiven us
all our transgression. Let us stand on
our feet.
Have you understood something?
Tell that neighbor the life of God is in
you.
Tell that neighbor when you're born
again,
you are born of God.
When you're born of something,
the life of that thing
is already in you.
Hallelujah.
Let's look at the book of John. John, I
think it's John chapter number 1 and
verse 3, or John chapter number 1 and
13.
Where the Bible says that we are born of
God. We are born from the Father.
John
Yes?
1:13
Who Who their birth neither to bloods,
nor to the will of the flesh, that of
the physical impulse, nor to the will of
man, that of a natural father, but to
God they are born of God. Hallelujah.
Whatever gives birth to you supplies its
life to you.
So so this cancels even the order of how
you are born. You are now born of God.
You carry the genes and the DNA of the
Father. Who are born not of the blood,
not of the will of the flesh, not of the
will of the man, but of God. By this
revelation, I want to declare the very
life of the Father, let it begin to move
in your life. This Zoe life, let that
life begin to move in your life. By this
revelation, the it is understanding that
begins to provoke men to live in certain
realities. I want to assure you that not
only were your sins forgiven, but there
was a supernatural encounter that
happened in your life, and that is the
life of God is in you. The Holy Spirit
dwells in you. God lives in you. That's
why the Bible says, "He that is in me is
greater than he that is in the world."
Dear Father, we thank you. We thank you
for this revelation. Just begin to thank
him. Lord, keep on OPENING UP THE EYES
OF OUR UNDERSTANDING. FLOOD OUR MINDS
WITH LIGHT. FLOOD OUR MINDS WITH LIGHT.
LET US BEGIN TO KNOW WHO WE ARE, OUR
IDENTITY IN CHRIST. WE ARE NOT JUST
ANOTHER PEOPLE. WE ARE A CHOSEN
GENERATION. WE BEAR AN IDENTITY IN YOU.
THANK YOU FOR the forgiveness of my
sins. THANK YOU FOR THE GREATER GIFT OF
ETERNAL LIFE. SOMEBODY JUST THANK HIM.
SOMETIMES WE LOOK AT EXTERNAL THINGS. We
look at cars. We look at mansions. They
are good, but if YOU BEGIN TO UNDERSTAND
THE DEPOSIT OF ETERNITY IN YOUR LIFE,
YOU WILL NEVER COMPLAIN. THE BIBLE SAYS,
"IF THE LORD COULD NOT WITHHOLD HIS ONLY
SON JESUS, HOW MUCH MORE THEN CAN HE
DO?" TODAY WE HAVE THE REVELATION THAT
THE SPIRIT DWELLS IN US. ANYONE THAT IS
BORN AGAIN, EVEN IF YOU DON'T PRAY IN
THE HOLY GHOST, SALVATION COMES BY THE
SPIRIT. BY THE DAY YOU SAID, "LORD, COME
INTO MY LIFE." HE CAME AND RESIDED INTO
YOUR LIFE. HE IS IN YOU. HE ABIDES IN
YOU. HE'S NOT AGAINST YOU. HE IS FOR
YOU. HE LOVES YOU. HE HAS FORGIVEN YOU.
HE HAS WASHED YOU. HE HAS DELIVERED YOU
FROM THE YOKES OF DARKNESS. HE HAS
JUSTIFIED, SANCTIFIED YOU. HE'S WALKING
YOU INTO PERFECTION. OH, YOU ARE THE
APPLE OF HIS EYE. HE HAS ENGRAVED YOUR
NAME ON THE PALM OF HIS HAND. HE KNOWS
THE NUMBER OF HAIR UPON YOUR HEAD. HE
LOVES YOU. HE HAS FIGURED OUT EVERYTHING
THAT IS CONNECTED TO YOUR LIFE. AS A
GOOD FATHER, AS A GOOD FATHER, HE SAYS,
"NO ONE CAN ASK OF HIS FATHER A BREAD
AND RECEIVE A STONE." HOW MUCH MORE IS
YOUR HEAVENLY FATHER? WE HAVE A FATHER
WHO IS BETTER THAN AN EARTHLY FATHER. WE
ARE BORN OF THE FATHER. THE VERY NATURE
AND THE VERY POWER, ELSE THE VERY
DIMENSION THAT IS IN GOD IS ALREADY
AVAILABLE IN US. I DECLARE BEGIN TO
MANIFEST THE DIMENSIONS OF THE FATHER.
WHEREVER THE LORD HAS KEPT YOU, THE
BIBLE SAYS, "I AM CREATED IN THE IMAGE
OF GOD." YOU BEAR THE IMAGE OF THE
FATHER. WHEN YOU LOOK AT YOUR LIFE, YOU
ARE A PROJECTION OF ETERNITY. THE BIBLE
SAYS, "DON'T YOU KNOW THAT YE ARE GODS?"
DON'T YOU KNOW THAT YE ARE GODS? YE ARE
GODS. YOU ARE NOT A MERE MAN WALKING ON
EARTH. THERE IS DIVINE EMPOWERMENT.
THERE IS DIVINE POWER. STOP LIVING LIKE
A CASUAL PERSON. VICTORY IS UPON YOUR
LIFE. DEMONS ARE ILLEGAL. ALL POWERS OF
DARKNESS ARE ILLEGAL IN YOUR AREA. BEGIN
TO RISE IN VICTORY. BEGIN TO RISE IN
POWER. DOMINION IS YOUR MANDATE. HE
SAID, "LET US MAKE MAN. LET US MAKE MAN.
LET THEM HAVE DOMINION. LET THEM HAVE
DOMINION. MULTIPLY. SUBDUE. INCREASE.
WE HAVE A MANDATE FROM ETERNITY. I
DECLARE IN THE NAME OF JESUS, YOU ARE
BORN OF GOD. THE GENESIS MANDATE HAS
ALREADY BEEN RESTORED BY THE POWER OF
CALVARY. WE ARE NOW THERE TO REIGN, TO
SUBDUE, TO TAKE OVER, TO CONQUER. GO AND
HAVE DOMINION. GO AND HAVE DOMINION.
JESUS SAID, "ALL POWER AND AUTHORITY HAS
BEEN GIVEN UNTO ME. SO SEND I THEE. GO
YE INTO TO THE WORLD, MAKING DISCIPLES,
CONVERTING THEM, BAPTIZING THEM IN THE
NAME OF THE FATHER, THE SON, AND THE
HOLY SPIRIT." THE BIBLE SAYS AND THE
DEMONS DEMANDED AND PERSUADED THAT THEY
SHOULD NOT BE SENT TO A BEAST, BUT JESUS
SAID, "I HAVE GIVEN YOU POWER TO TRAMPLE
OVER SERPENT, TO TRAMPLE OVER SCORPIONS.
THEY WILL NOT HARM YOU." THE BOOK OF
MARK TELLS US THAT IF WE BELIEVE IN THE
NAME OF JESUS, WE SHALL CAST OUT DEVILS.
IN THE NAME OF JESUS, WE SHALL SPEAK IN
A NEW TONGUE. IF WE BELIEVE, WE WILL
TAKE DEADLY POISON. IT WILL NOT HARM US.
WE WILL STEP ON SERPENTS AND SCORPIONS
AND THEY SHALL NOT HARM US. NOT ONLY DO
WE BELIEVE, BUT WE ARE IN HIM. IF CHRIST
BE IN ME, JESUS IN ME, THE HOPE OF ALL
GLORY.
THE BIBLE SAYS HE MADE A PUBLIC
SPECTACLE BY DISARMING THE DEVIL ON THE
MOUNTAINS OF CALVARY, A PUBLIC
SPECTACLE. SHAKATALIA, BARONTALIA, BEGIN
TO DECLARE VICTORY. YOU ARE A WINNER.
YOU ARE A CONQUEROR. YOU ARE MORE THAN A
CONQUEROR. YOU ARE VICTORIOUS.
SHANDE BRADIA, SOMEBODY AFFIRM IT,
CONFESS IT, SPEAK IT, AFFIRM IT IN YOUR
LIFE. REPALONDA, THE KINGDOM OF DARKNESS
CANNOT PREVAIL OVER YOUR LIFE. YOU ARE A
CHILD OF GOD. YOU ARE THE REDEEMED OF
THE FATHER. YOU ARE THE RIGHTEOUSNESS OF
GOD. YOU ARE LOVED. YOU ARE THE BELOVED
OF ELOHIM. ZIKAPALATALIA,
REPALIADA, RIKAPALIASADALIA,
MANDELIBRA, THE ONE THAT WATCHES OVER
YOU, NEITHER SLEEPS NOR SLUMBERS. HIS
EARS ARE ATTENTIVE. ANYTIME YOU CALL, HE
SAYS, "I WILL BE WITH YOU TO THE CLOSE
OF THE AGE. I WILL NEVER LEAVE YOU NOR
FORSAKE YOU. NOT ONLY AM I WITH YOU, BUT
I'M ALSO IN YOU." SHAMANDELIA,
RAKAPALIABADA.
JESUS SAID, "LORD, MAY THEY BE ONE JUST
AS WE ARE ONE, THAT I AM IN THEM AND
THEY ARE IN ME. AS I AM IN YOU, YOU ARE
IN JESUS. YOU ARE IN THE FATHER BECAUSE
JESUS IS IN YOU." IT IS A COMPLEX
MATRIX, BUT WHERE YOU ARE, YOU ARE
HIDDEN IN CHRIST.
SHATALIBRASOBALIA.
I have a father.
He knows my name.
I have a maker.
I want us to DECLARE BECAUSE THERE IS
ONE THAT KNOWS YOU. IS SOMEONE GETTING
ME?
IS SOMEONE GETTING ME?
I I THIS ONE, I DON'T KNOW how it will
go.
Holy Spirit, give us direction.
Because as I was preaching,
I sensed a LOT OF DARKNESS.
DARKNESS DOES NOT MEAN DEMONIC, it means
absence of revelation.
The Bible says fill their mind with
light.
FILL THEIR MIND WITH LIGHT.
IN THE BOOK OF EPHESIANS CHAPTER NUMBER
ONE UH IN VERSE 18, THE BIBLE SAYS TO
FILL THEIR MIND IN THE MESSAGE VERSION,
IT SAYS FILL THEIR MINDS WITH LIGHT.
FILL THEIR MINDS WITH LIGHT, WISDOM AND
UNDERSTANDING. THERE IS LIGHT THAT CAN
COME IN THE MIND OF THE believer that to
receive the accurate knowledge of who
they are. WE CAN NEVER FULFILL DESTINY
WITH a wrong identity.
Every declaration we make, IF A MAN DOES
NOT KNOW WHO HE IS IN CHRIST, THAT
ASSIGNMENT IS DEAD ON ARRIVAL. IT IS
YOUR IDENTITY FIRST BEFORE EVEN
ASSIGNMENT.
THE BIBLE SAYS YOUR NO, YOUR EYES BEING
ENLIGHTENED, THAT SCRIPTURE THE WAY you
have put it it was okay.
Your eyes focus and clear so that YOU
CAN SEE EXACTLY. THE EYES OF
UNDERSTANDING BEING ENLIGHTENED. IN IN
ANOTHER VERSION HE SAID, "FILLING THEIR
MINDS WITH LIGHT."
THAT MEANS TAKING AWAY THE DARKNESS.
Because there is a veil
that can cover the mind of a man.
We refuse to come to church and leave
the way we are.
Please tell that neighbor he's in you.
Tell that neighbor he's in you.
Can I share something before we even
declare this song?
You see
I saw this.
So this is the Holy Spirit.
He's in you.
He's the one that teaches us and reminds
us
of all the things.
Who is the Holy Spirit?
The writer and the one that inspired
the writers of scripture.
So the one that wrote the scripture is
in you.
So do you know
you know, but you don't know.
Okay.
I don't know how I'll put it.
Because if this is the Holy Spirit in
me,
the one that inspired the scripture,
so I know, but I don't know.
So I have to move this reality to now my
realm.
Many of the things we are waiting for,
they are not from above, they are from
within.
It is a pulling
ah.
I know that I know, BUT I DON'T know how
I know, but I know.
THERE IS A THAT'S WHAT WE CALL THE
WITNESS of the spirit.
DO YOU KNOW A MAN CAN PROPHESY TO YOU,
PASTOR EUGENE, AND YOU BEGIN to cry,
and ask, "How did he know?"
Because there I used to sense it. I
THERE WAS A WITNESS IN MY SPIRIT, BUT
HE'S confirming it.
THERE THERE'S ABOUT TO BE AN INSIDE
OUTBURST EXPLOSION.
OH, YOU YOU HAVE NOT YET MET YOU.
YOU HAVE NOT YET MET YOU. YOU THINK YOU
KNOW YOURSELF. YOU HAVE NOT YET MET YOU
ACCORDING TO THE DEPOSITS OF THE SPIRIT.
SOME OF YOU ARE HEALERS.
YET YOU HAVE AN INHALER. AN INHALER.
BECAUSE YOU HAVE NEVER KNOWN THAT THAT
POWER
IS IN ME.
SOME OF YOU OH MY GOD, THE DIMENSIONS OF
GOD THAT ARE HIDDEN IN YOU, THEY ARE SO
HEAVY. YOU ARE LOOKING TO GOD, GOD IS
looking unto you saying, "The day you
discover who you are is the day you will
recover what you have lost." BECAUSE
THERE IS A RECOVERY THAT COMES WITH
DISCOVERY. I DECLARE, EVEN AS WE GO
DURING THE WEEK, MAY THE LORD BEGIN TO
REVEAL who you are. YOU ARE NOT A LOSER,
YOU ARE NOT A FAILURE, YOU ARE NOT A
STATISTICS, YOU ARE NOT ANOTHER YOUNG
MAN WALKING IN LIFE, YOU ARE THE SON OF
GOD. I SAY YOU ARE THE SON OF GOD. YOU
ARE THE HOPE OF YOUR FAMILY. YOU ARE THE
SOLUTION TO GENERATIONS. WHEREVER YOU
ENTER, YOU ARE NOT BORN BY THE WILL OF A
MAN AND A WOMAN, YOU ARE BORN BY THE
DESIRES OF HEAVEN. LET THAT WHICH IS IN
YOU, THE ANCIENT DEPOSIT IN YOUR SPIRIT,
MAY THE HOLY GHOST BEGIN TO REVEAL THEM.
LET THERE BE AN OUTBURST. LET THE REAL
YOU BEGIN TO MANIFEST.
WE ALL CAME WITH ORDINARY HANDS UNTIL
SOME OF US DISCOVERED THAT THESE HANDS
ARE THE HANDS OF JESUS. THEY CAN BE LAID
ON MEN AND THEY GET HEALED. ALL OF US WE
CAME WITH ORDINARY SPEECH UNTIL SOME OF
US DISCOVERED THAT MY SPEECH CAN PREACH
THE GOSPEL. WE ALL CAME ORDINARY, BUT BY
THE POWER OF GOD, YOU ARE ABOUT TO BE AN
EXTRAORDINARY MAN. ONE THAT HAS NEVER
EXISTED. IF ANYONE BE IN CHRIST, HE IS A
NEW CREATION. THERE IS A VERSION OF YOU
THAT HAS NEVER EXISTED. THAT VERSION
CANNOT CARRY GENERATIONAL CURSES. THERE
IS A VERSION, IF ANYONE BE IN CHRIST, HE
IS A NEW CREATION. THERE IS A MAN YOU
HAVE NEVER MET. THERE IS A MAN YOU HAVE
NEVER MET. THERE IS A DIMENSION OF YOU
YOU HAVE NEVER INTERACTED. IF ANYONE BE
IN CHRIST, HE IS A NEW CREATION, NOT A
REFURBISHED.
YOU ARE NOT SCRAP METAL THAT WAS MELTED
TO BECOME DIFFERENT. YOU ARE A BEING
THAT NEVER EXISTED. IN THE GENOS IN YOUR
FAMILY, YOUR KIND HAS NEVER EXISTED. YOU
DON'T BEAR THE NAME OF YOUR GRANDFATHER.
YOU ARE A MYSTERY TO THAT FAMILY. YOU
DON'T CARRY THE NAME OF YOUR
GRANDMOTHER. YOU ARE A MYSTERY TO THAT
FAMILY. WHEN YOU BECAME A NEW MAN, IT
WILL TAKE THE ONE THAT MADE YOU NEW TO
TELL YOU WHO YOU ARE. YOU HAVE NOT YET
UNDERSTOOD WHO YOU ARE.
MY GOD, LIMURU LIMURU BECAUSE WHEN I
CAME to Limuru the Lord TOLD ME, "YOU
ARE NOT RUNNING A CHURCH. YOU ARE
RUNNING A GLOBAL MINISTRY IN A VILLAGE."
I REALIZED IT'S NOT THE LOCATION.
EPHESIANS CHAPTER NUMBER 1 AND VERSE 1,
THE BIBLE SAYS I WRITE TO YOU SAINTS IN
EPHESUS, BUT I WRITE TO YOU FAITHFULS
WHO ARE IN CHRIST. YOU CAN BE IN
EPHESUS, BUT WE ARE ALL IN CHRIST.
GEOGRAPHICAL LOCATION IS NOT AS
IMPORTANT AS YOUR SPIRITUAL LOCATION.
THIS IS THE LETTER FROM PAUL, CHOSEN BY
THE WILL OF GOD TO BE AN APOSTLE OF
CHRIST. I AM WRITING TO GOD HOLY PEOPLE.
WHERE ARE THEY?
WHO ARE FAITHFUL? LOOK FOR KJV,
FOLLOWERS OF CHRIST JESUS. THE BIBLE
SAYS WHO ARE ALSO IN CHRIST.
GIVE ME IN KJV, PLEASE, QUICKLY. I am
working on borrowed time, BUT I HAVE TO
ANNOUNCE IT. PAUL, AN APOSTLE OF JESUS
CHRIST, BY THE WILL of God, TO THE
SAINTS
TO THE SAINTS
WHICH ARE IN LIMURU
AND TO THE FAITHFUL
IN
in
If there is A BELIEVER IN AMERICA, THEY
ARE ALSO IN CHRIST. IF THERE IS A
BELIEVER IN TANZANIA, THEY ARE ALSO IN
CHRIST. THERE IS A PLACE THAT EQUALIZES
ALL OF US. I COULD BE IN LIMURU, BUT I'M
IN CHRIST. SO, THE LORD, IF I'M IN
CHRIST, IT IS NOT ABOUT LOCATION.
BECAUSE WE COME FROM A THIRD WORLD
COUNTRY, WHAT CHANGES THE MATRIX?
WHATEVER IS IN CHRIST CAN CHANGE LIMURU.
LIMURU CANNOT CHANGE CHRIST.
I WISH I HAD A CHURCH TODAY.
AH.
LIMURU CANNOT CHANGE CHRIST.
BUT THE POWER THAT IS CHANGING NIGERIA,
THE POWER THAT IS CHANGING AMERICA, THE
POWER THAT IS CHANGING THE WORLD, THAT
POWER IS ALSO IN YOU.
SO YOU DON'T NEED TO RELOCATE, YOU NEED
TO MANIFEST.
BECAUSE SOMEONE CAUGHT IT IN AMERICA,
THEY ARE NOW MANIFESTING IT IN AMERICA.
THIS SAME GOSPEL IS BEING PREACHED.
CARRIERS OF THE SAME JESUS ARE BUILDING
CITIES.
WHAT IS IT THAT I'VE NOT KNOWN? BECAUSE
WE CAN GROW IN CHRIST. WE CAN ALL BE IN
CHRIST, BUT WE CAN GROW IN CHRIST. THE
PROBLEM OF MANIFESTATION IS THE LEVEL OF
GROWTH.
That's the difference.
Hi.
So I bless the Lord.
BECAUSE IT'S NOT CONVENIENCE.
IT'S NOT CONVENIENCE.
AND ON THIS MOUNTAIN, BECAUSE we are in
Christ.
The owner of the globe.
We are here to manifest globally.
TELL YOUR NEIGHBOR, TELL YOUR NEIGHBOR.
OUR GOD IS NOT A LOCAL GOD.
HE'S A GLOBAL GOD.
BEGIN TO SEE THE WORLD as your platform
of operation.
I BEGAN BY SAYING, LIFT YOUR FAITH TO
THE level where you can interact with
God. WHEN THE BIBLE SAYS COME AND LET US
REASON, IT means kuna time Mungu
hatakuja kwa level yako.
Sijui kama MNA SHIKA.
KUNA TIME WATU WANANGOJA MUNGU AKUJE.
AONE VITU NINAONA HAPA CHINI. MUNGU
ANASEMA AH RONI. NIKIONA VILE UNAONA.
HAUTABADILIKA. WEWE SASA KUJA KUJA. WEWE
KUJA.
KUJA NDIO TU REASON. BECAUSE UKO CHINI
WHATEVER YOU ARE SEEING NI COMPETITION
YA DUMBELI.
WEWE UNAONA DUMBELI. NA KIA MICHAEL.
MUNGU ANAKUAMBIA THERE IS DUBAI TO BE
TAKEN. THERE IS QATAR TO BE TAKEN. THERE
IS ETHIOPIA TO BE TAKEN. THEN AKIKUWEKA
HAPA. ANAKUAMBIA SASA TU REASON. NI NINI
UNAONA? UNAMWAMBIA UKO CHINI NILIKUWA
NAONA KIA MICHAEL BUTALI.
DUMBELI.
AH. KUWAPI KWINGINE? MORENGE. T. SIASA
ZA HUKU SIASA ZA HUKU. THE MOMENT
UMESIMAMA HAPA. UNAMWAMBIA NAONA
AUSTRALIA. ANAKUAMBIA YOU'RE SEEING
WELL. NAONA CHINA ANAKUAMBIA YOU'RE
SEEING WELL. NAONA MATAIFA. THAT'S WHY
HE SAYS COME.
IF I REASON WITHIN YOUR LEVEL. YOU WILL
NOT UNDERSTAND THE THINGS I'M SAYING. SO
THERE IS A LEVEL WE MUST LIFT OUR FAITH.
LET US NOT FOCUS ON AFFLICTIONS. LET US
FOCUS ON HIM. I LIFT MY EYES. UNTO
JESUS. THE AUTHOR. AND THE FINISHER. OF
MY FAITH. HE THAT BEGAN. GOD A GOOD WORK
IN YOU. IS FAITHFUL ENOUGH TO BRING IT
TO COMPLETION. HE IS THE ALPHA AND THE
OMEGA. THE FIRST AND THE LAST. THE
BEGINNING AND THE END. HE IS THE ONE
THAT I SERVE. COME.
THE VISION ON THE VALLEY.
IS NOT THE VISION ON THE MOUNTAIN.
THAT'S WHY THE LORD HAD TO TAKE MOSES ON
A HIGH PLACE. AND TELL HIM THAT'S the
promised land.
IN THE VALLEY THEY SAW OPPOSITION. ON
THE MOUNTAIN HE SAW THE PROMISE. WHERE
YOU STAND MATTERS.
THAT'S WHY THERE ARE MEN WHEN THE BIBLE
SAYS LET THE WEAK SAY THAT I'M POOR. IT
IS NOT THAT THEY ARE NOT IT'S NOT THAT
THE REALITY OF WEAKNESS IS NOT THERE.
THEY HAVE ASCENDED TO A DIMENSION. THEY
HAVE SEEN THEIR FUTURE IN CHRIST. SO
THEY CANNOT CONFESS THEIR REALITY. THEY
CAN ONLY CONFESS THEIR DESTINATION. LET
THE WEAK SAY THAT I'M POOR. LET THE WEAK
SAY THAT THAT I'M STRONG. LET THE POOR
SAY THAT I'M RICH BECAUSE THEY HAVE SEEN
THE WEALTH. WE ARE BLESSED WITH ALL
SPIRITUAL BLESSINGS IN CHRIST JESUS.
So there's a place WE NEED TO STAND
AND SEE WHAT GOD is saying.
AND THAT WILL SHIFT OUR BATTLES.
THE BATTLE OF A MAN BUILDING A NATION
CANNOT BE INTERRUPTED BY A CHIEF IN A
VILLAGE.
I KNOW A MAN OF GOD.
AND A SENIOR POLITICIAN
VERY SENIOR IN THAT TERRITORY WANTED THE
LAND.
The church is in town.
AND HE MADE ALL DEALS WITH THE COUNTY
so that the church CAN BE DEMOLISHED.
I GOT TO go because he was praying. He
said if they destroy this church, let
them destroy when I'm on the altar.
Then he was told the thing guys are
here.
He went and told the guy,
you can't touch this church.
It is bigger than that man.
And he told him, I hope we may bunker
quacko.
Juma zishik alikiba.
The man did not finish 3 days.
He died.
Tingas it is your account.
I got charged atmosphere.
Siku ya pili wakasema sasa the next year
wakakutana sasa wamepanga kila kitu.
Documents forge everything.
Then they were reminded, the man who
tried to drive that tractor died.
What kind of akajali buku gurumisha
tinga ikakata.
Today, the politician who was fighting
him died. The man has the land.
That's the victory we are talking about.
Siafu niambie wewe ndio ulihama mchawi
akaishi. Tutakugurudisha uko. Na
tukulipie rent. Mpakwe kuji na ushuhuda
ya hii maandiko.
Kwa sababu yesu AMBAYE TUNAMWAMINI
HAJAHI FAIL. HAIZI ANZA NA WEWE. YOU
CANNOT BE THE FIRST ONE TO WRITE A
TESTIMONY OF FAILURE. IF YOU HAVE THE
POWER, IT MUST MANIFEST. WHEREVER YOU
ARE, GO AND MANIFEST THE KINGDOM. GO AND
TAKE THE TERRITORY. GO AND KILL THE
WITCHES AND FIRE THEM. ANY POWER THAT
OPERATES IN YOUR TERRITORY, I PERMIT YOU
AS A CHILD OF GOD, GO AND SECURE THE
TERRITORY FOR JESUS. IN THE NAME OF
JESUS. HE THAT IS IN YOU, HE THAT IS IN
YOU IS GREATER THAN THE ONE THAT IS IN
THE WORLD.
I KNOW WHO I AM.
I HAVE
I KNOW WHO I AM. WIMBO IMEBADILIKA.
KILA ATMOSPHERE IKO NA SOUND YAKE.
I'M WALKING